<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Charles Ancheta Blog</title>
        <link>https://charlesancheta.com/blog</link>
        <description>Charles Ancheta Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bye bye Netlify]]></title>
            <link>https://charlesancheta.com/blog/bye-bye-netlify</link>
            <guid>bye-bye-netlify</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It was short trial, but GitHub Pages just works better for me.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was short trial, but GitHub Pages just works better for me.</p><p>A couple of weeks ago, I moved my website from GitHub Pages to Netlify, hoping
for a better development and production experience. I didn't really have a need
to move just yet, but I wanted to see what the buzz about Netlify was about. So
I spent a few hours setting it up and pointing my domain to the Netlify app.</p><p>It was working just fine at first, until I started making updates. The page
would just load indefinitely and I would have to visit <code>cbebe.netlify.app</code>
first before <code>charlesancheta.com</code> would behave properly. I've had a few
embarrassing moments showing my website to people for a couple times and it
refusing to load.</p><p>Another annoying was that every pull request and push to the master branch
would trigger a build, even if none of the pages were modified. Netlify only
provides a limited about of build time every month, so I found myself
cancelling more builds in the Netlify dashboard more often than I manually
deployed a build using the command line. This could be nice if other people
were contributing to this repo, but since this is a personal website, I find
that unlikely.</p><p>Realizing these, I moved back to GitHub Pages and manually deploying with the
CLI. Maybe in the future where I would have to actually launch a
production-level static website that I would revisit Netlify, but for now, I'll
stick with my current workflow.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>netlify</category>
            <category>hosting</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Friendship Ended with TypeScript, now Go is My Best Friend]]></title>
            <link>https://charlesancheta.com/blog/2022/06/07/friendship-ended</link>
            <guid>/2022/06/07/friendship-ended</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Friendship ended]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Friendship ended" src="/assets/images/friendship-ended-81753b98ed56ffb6ff2b0c00e7f78cf0.webp" width="680" height="510" class="img_DCeH"></p><p>No blog post here, just a quick edit I made in GIMP.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>dev</category>
            <category>go</category>
            <category>typescript</category>
            <category>backend</category>
            <category>meme</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TIL: My actual height]]></title>
            <link>https://charlesancheta.com/blog/til/my-actual-height</link>
            <guid>til/my-actual-height</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Today I learned what my actual height was (at least at the time of writing).]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today I learned what my actual height was (at least at the time of writing).
For a few years now I've always kind of just stuck with 170 cm because that's
what was in my driver's license when I got it 5 years ago (I really need to
pass the road test this year). I'm not even sure if that was right at the time.</p><p>So, I took a couple of IKEA measuring tapes (courtesy of Jherzey), put them
together on a post in our basement, got a square ruler (triangular?
(<!-- -->*<!-- -->sigh<!-- -->*<!-- -->...
<a href="https://philnews.ph/2021/06/10/eskwala-in-english-translate-eskwala-in-english/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>eskwala</em></a>))
and measured my height.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="A square measuring my height at 173 cm" src="/assets/images/173cm-878f5d7a25cfd68eb8a8389497e78c23.webp" width="1536" height="2048" class="img_DCeH"></p><p>So I guess I grew 3 cm in those 5 years? I still haven't caught up to my dad's
peak height (176 cm), but he's a bit shorter now that he's older, so it's okay.
My hair can add at least 2 inches 😂.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>til</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome!]]></title>
            <link>https://charlesancheta.com/blog/welcome</link>
            <guid>welcome</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to my website! I am Charles, a Computer Engineering Student working as]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my website! I am Charles, a Computer Engineering Student working as
a Full Stack Web Developer.</p><p>For someone who spends a lot of time typing in front of a computer, I write
down very little of my thoughts. Most stuff that I come back to for memories
are just old code and old pictures, and this should hopefully change that.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>welcome</category>
            <category>first</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>